喂  那边有人吗
Hello? Is anybody out here?
计时开始
All right.
表示"超然的"12个字母单词
12-letter word for "Transcendent."
超凡脱俗
Otherworldly.
坦白说  出题人有时根本就没用脑子嘛
Honestly, sometimes it's like they're not even trying.
用笔做猜字游戏呢
Doing the crossword in pen?
今天自我感觉良好  是吧
Feeling cocky today, are we?
没挑战的生活哪有意思
What is life without challenges?
表示"离间"的8个字母单词
8-letter word for "Estrange."
啊  我的小同义词典  你来得刚刚好
Ah! You are just in time, my mini thesaurus.
给我想个表示"离间"的8个字母单词
I need an 8-letter word for "Estrange."
儿子  她听不到你说话
She doesn't hear you, darling.
她还在跟阿什利讲电话
She's still talking to Ashley.
我真该算算这通电话的时长
I should be timing that phone call.
-肯定能破世界纪录  -看开点
- That's gotta be a record. - Please.
这通电话可比我任一场恋情都要长
I've had relationships that didn't last this long.
那是
True.
好的  拜拜
Okay. Bye.
抱歉  我们正在聊下周六远足的事
Sorry. We were talking about the hiking trip next Saturday.
那阿什利征得父母同意让他
Oh, has Ashley got the all clear from his parents
随我们出游吗
to come with us?
他父母说想先见见你
They say they want to meet you first.
他们一定是想好好审视我
Ah, they want to vet me to make sure
怕我在遭遇岩崩等灾难时
if there's some kind of rock slide,
扔下他们的乖儿子受困于山腰
that I won't leave their boy stranded on a mountainside,
害他只能咬断手臂逃生
having to gnaw off his own arm to survive.
那你肯去见面咯
So you'll do it?
我们会请他们过来吃晚饭
We'll have them over for dinner.
跟他们攀关系  留个好印象
We'll schmooze and impress them.
你们需要我来下厨吗
Would you like me to cook something?
不用  我们想给人家留个好印象
No, we want to impress them.
你这话是什么意思
And what is that supposed to mean?
终于到了"见家长"环节了  卡塞尔
So it's "meet the parents" time, huh, Castle?
这对你来说是很关键的一刻
This is a pretty critical moment for you.
对我  为什么是我
For me? Why me?
我是说  阿什利是阿丽克西斯的初恋  对吧
Well, I mean, Ashley is Alexis' first love, right?
嗯
Mm-hmm.
那么  要是双方父母处不好
Well, what do you think will happen
你觉得会发生什么事呢
if you don't get on with his parents?
她会对他失去兴趣
She'll lose interest in him?
不对  恰恰相反
Oh, no. The exact opposite.
那只会让他们感到恋情受阻
I mean, it'll make their romance feel forbidden,
做出一些你想不到的事
and they'll be off doing god knows what.
相信我  我是过来人
Trust me. I know.
我从没往那方面想过
I never thought of it that way.
我的建议是和她男朋友走近点
My advice is keep the boyfriend close
和他的父母走更近点
but the parents closer.
嘿  伙计们
Hey, guys.
-是什么案子  -有人死了
- What do we got? - Something messed up.
我从没见过这种死法
I've never seen anything like it.
死者叫玛丽·苏巴拉奥  35岁
Victim's name is Marie Subbarao. She's 35.
保安昨晚发现她死于车内
Security guard found her last night.
人至今还没恢复过来
Still getting over it.
哇  她看上去好像撑胀了的腊肠
Wow. She looks like an overstuffed sausage.
蕾妮  她怎么会变成这样的
Lanie, what the hell happened to her?
这叫暴发性减压
It's called explosive decompression.
减什么压  什么造成的
From what? What would cause this?
这是人体暴露在真空环境下的结果
It's a result of exposure to a zero-atmosphere environment.
真空  外太空那种真空吗
Zero atmosphere? As in... Outer space?
对
Yep.
又或者是...
Or?
亲爱的  我暂时给不出别的可能性
I don't have an "Or" for you right now, sweetie.
我要把她的尸体运回验尸房
I have to get her body back to the morgue,
才有可能得出别的结论
and then I may have some answers.
行  那么她的尸体在车里
Okay, well, her body's in a car
车子停在铁路站场中间
in the middle of the rail yard,
显然她不是在外太空被杀的
so clearly she wasn't killed in outer space.
势必会有别的解释的
There's gotta be another explanation.
看看这个  她在看这本
Check this out-- she was reading
《第四类接触》  说的是外星人绑架的事
"Taken by the fourth kind," a book on alien abductions.
那你的想法是什么  卡塞尔
So what's your theory, Castle,
难不成她是遭外星人绑架并杀害的吗
that she was abducted and then killed by aliens?
更合理的说法应该是
Mm. The story that makes more sense
外星人绑架她时出了差错
is, uh, alien abduction gone wrong--
结果玛丽被意外炸出了
one that ends with Marie being accidentally blasted
外星飞船的气闸
out of the air lock of the alien spaceship.
要凶手真是外星人  他可是尼古丁成瘾者
Well, if it was E.T., he has a nicotine addiction.
我们在后轮胎旁找到这根烟蒂
We found this cigarette butt by the rear tire.
它就掉着车痕上
It was laying in the track,
也就是说这根烟蒂是停车后才扔掉的
which means it was dropped after the car was parked.
好的  让鉴证人员检查上面的DNA
All right. Well, have C.S.U. check for D.N.A.
也许能查出疑犯
Maybe we'll get lucky.
另外  能不能查一下什么会造成
And can you look into explosive decompression,
-暴发性减压  -没问题
- see what else might cause it? - You got it.
谢谢
Thank you.
你不得不承认
You do have to admit,
她的死状看来确实很...超凡脱俗
her condition does seem... otherworldly.
玛丽·苏巴拉奥
Marie Subbarao...
生前的样子
the before version.
在芝加哥出生
Born in Chicago,
是约翰霍普金斯大学的研究生
did postgrad work at Johns Hopkins,
在两年前
then two years ago,
她在市中心的奥布里科学中心找到一份
she takes a job at the Aubrey Science Center in midtown
天体物理学家的工作
as an astrophysicist.
具体是做什么呢
Doing what?
我也不太确定
I'm not really sure.
根据中心官网说
According to the center's web site,
她最近得到SETI学会的一笔拨款
she recently landed a grant from the SETI Institute.
是指"搜寻地外文明计划"么
The search for extraterrestrial intelligence SETI?
-那就解释了...  -解释不了
- That could explain why-- - No, it couldn't.
那她为SETI工作只是一个难得的巧合吗
So her working for SETI is just a wild coincidence?
听我说  这只是一个跟本案
I'm saying, it's an interesting fact
无关的有趣的事实
that is unrelated to our case.
外星人跟玛丽·苏巴拉奥的死毫无关系
Aliens were not involved in Marie Subbarao's death.
这很难说
Uh, I don't know.
怎么说呢  莱恩警探
Why, detective Ryan,
没想到你也相信有外星人
I never figured you for a believer.
我只记得一件事  某天晚上我爸的表亲
All I know is, my father's cousin Raymond
雷蒙德离开在纽泽西的聚会后
left this party in Jersey one night.
就在开车回皇后区途中  突然间
He's driving back to Queens, and bam!
一团刺眼的白光从天而降
Blinding bright light comes down from the sky,
当他醒来时  已是早上
next thing he knows, it's morning,
自己则躺在纽泽西高速公路旁
he's on the side of the Jersey turnpike.
我来猜猜  事后他什么都不记得了
Let me guess. No memory of what happened.
那不叫外星人绑架
That is not called an alien abduction.
那叫宿醉
That is called a hangover.
有可能
Maybe.
因为雷蒙德一直是家里最无足轻重的人
Raymond always was the lightweight in the family.
说到家庭
Speaking of family,
本案的死者有家人吗  结婚了吗
did our victim have any, a husband maybe?
邻居说她未婚  是一个人住
Neighbors say she was single and lived alone.
他们很少见到她
They barely saw her.
显然她一般是
Apparently, she normally came home
晚上10点左右下班回到家
from work around 10:00 P.M.
蕾妮说死亡时间是晚上9点左右
Lanie said that the time of death was around 9:00 P.M.,
也就是说公司也许是最后一个
which means work was the last place
有人见到她还活着的地方
that she was probably seen alive.
太难以置信了
This is unbelievable.
玛丽是公司最具天赋的研究员之一
Marie was one of my most gifted researchers.
她在这里具体从事什么工作
What did she do here exactly?
她负责分析从新墨西哥的
Uh, she analyzed the data
射电望远镜接收到的数据
fed in from our radio telescope in New Mexico,
研究类星射电源的辐射
studying radiation from quasars.
是为SETI学会做研究吗
For the SETI institute?
不  她的大部分工作与美国太空总署相关
No. Most of her work was NASA related.
你最后一次见到她是在什么时候
And when was the last time you saw her?
昨晚
Uh, last night.
我7点下班时她还在办公室里
She was still here at her office at 7 when I left.
那么你呢  豪德小姐
And what about you, Ms. Holder?
噢  我们查看了下周的日程表
Oh, we went over the calendar for next week,
然后在7:30她就让我下班了
and then she sent me home at 7:30.
她有没有什么生活上的问题
Was she having any problems in life?
她最近有反常的举动吗
Anything unusual happening lately?
我没看出什么不妥
Not that I'm aware of.
其实...
Actually...
从周一开始  她就表现得十分紧张不安
since Monday, she'd been acting anxious and uptight.
我后来问她发生什么事了  她说
I finally asked her what was wrong, and she said
她正经历着命运的大转折
that something life-changing had happened to her.
-什么转折  -我不知道
- What was it? - I don't know.
然后到了周三  她在中午便早早下班
Then on Wednesday, she left work in the middle of the day.
直到周四早上才见到她人
She didn't come back until Thursday morning.
沃恩博士  玛丽的尸体
Dr. Vaughn, Marie's body
表现出暴发性减压的症候
showed signs of explosive decompression.
她有没有在进行什么
Was she doing any kind of research
与此相关的研究呢
that would account for that?
我的天啊
Oh, my god.
那是"有"的意思
That's a yes.
这是一个高空模拟低压舱
It's called an altitude chamber.
我们用它来为美国太空总署
We use it to study
研究减压环境下的
thermal life support systems
热控生命保障系统
under reduced pressure for NASA.
如果人跑到里面会发生什么事
What would happen if a person went inside?
没穿保护装置的话
Without protective gear?
肺部会因气体膨胀而破裂
Your lungs rupture from gas expansion
人体内所有水分都会被蒸发掉
and all the liquid in your body evaporates.
也就是除去看不到外太空  能感受到
So all the horrible effects of outer space
外太空的一切可怕效应
without the view.
谁有权进入这个区域
Who else had access to this area?
大多数研究员及其助手都可以
Mostly our researchers and their assistants.
总共  大概35人
Maybe 35 people in all.
我需要他们所有人的名单
I'll need a list of all of their names.
玛丽跟他们任何人有过节吗
Did Marie have problems with any of them?
泰德·卡特
Ted Carter...
她的前男友
Her ex-boyfriend.
他们分手后  闹得很难看
After their breakup, things got ugly between them.
能问问找我来有何贵干吗
Can I ask what this is about?
卡特先生
Mr. Carter...
昨晚7:42  你曾刷卡
Your key card was swiped at the science center
进入了科技馆
last night at 7:42.
能告诉我们你为何要去那里吗
You mind tell us what you were doing there?
-我是去找人的  -玛丽  苏巴拉奥吗
- I went to see someone.  - Marie Subbarao?
这与你们有何相干
Why is this any of your business?
我们在调查她的谋杀案
We're investigating her murder.
什么
What?
玛丽又没死
Marie's not dead.
她怎么可能死了
How could she be dead?
有人把她关进了低压舱
Someone put her in an altitude chamber.
天呐
Oh, my god.
谁会做出这种事啊
Who could've done something like that?
她是九点左右遇害的
She was killed at around 9:00 p.M.,
就在你离开后不久
not long after you arrived at the center.
不是我  不是我干的
Not me. It wasn't me.
你们怎么能认为我会做出这种事
How could you think I would do something like that?
你有动机
You had motive.
你还有进出低压舱的权限
You had access to the chamber.
不然你为什么要去见她
Why else would you even go and se e her?
我是去邀请她共进晚餐的
To ask her to dinner.
她跟你分了手  还害你被开除了  我猜...
After Marie dumped you and had you fired. I hope--
不是那样的  是我主动辞职的
It wasn't like that. I quit.
每天跟她抬头不见低头见  实在太痛苦了
It was too painful to be around her.
没想到周三的时候  她突然打给了我
Then on Wednesday, out of nowhere, she called me.
她想去喝咖啡
She wanted to go to coffee.
为什么
Now why would she do that?
我猜想  是为了跟我和解
To mend fences, I-I guess.
她还了我几件旧T恤
She gave me back some old T-shirts,
还有我的几张CD
some CDs she had of mine,
她说为我俩之前的分手方式感到抱歉
said she felt bad about the way things ended.
我以为我们也许还有机会
I thought maybe we still had a chance, you know?
所以我就去馆里找她了
So I went looking for her at the center.
-你找到她之后发生了什么  -没什么
- What happened when you found her?  - Nothing.
我们就聊了一小会
We talked for a few seconds.
她看起来有些沮丧
She seemed upset about something.
我试着想弄清原因
I-I tried to find out what,
可她正急着要去什么地方  所以我就走了
but she was in a hurry to get somewhere, so I left.
我回家了
I went home.
我八点就离开那里了
I-I was there by 8:00.
把这儿当家吧
Make yourself at home.
你得在这儿待上一阵子了
You're gonna be here for a while.
鉴证组正在检查低压舱
C.S.U. is going through the altitude chamber.
只要他们能带回举证证据
Once they get back with forensics,
我们就能起诉泰德·卡特了
we should be able to charge Ted Carter.
跟我解释下
Tell me this...
卡特是怎么把尸体弄去铁路站场的
How did Carter get the body to the rail yard?
那个低压舱
Well, the altitude chamber
是紧挨着停车场的
is right next to the parking garage,
所以他可能先把尸体扔到了车上
so he probably dumped her body in the car,
然后开车送去了铁路站场
took it out to the rail yard,
试图让我们追踪不到
and tried to throw us off the trail.
知道怎么解释更合理吗
You know what would be a better story?
这起神秘事件只是地球人所为
We have an earthbound solution to this mystery,
你很失望  我明白
and you are disappointed. I get it.
可这个  不是吧
But that, really?
拜托  玛丽说她遇到了改变人生的大事
Come on. Marie said she had a life-changing event.
还有什么比碰上这家伙
What could be more life changing
更能改变人生呢
than being beamed up by this guy?
得了吧  卡塞尔
Come on, Castle.
咱们都清楚  根本没有外星人绑架这档子事
We all know that there is no such thing as alien abductions.
可是  大部分被绑架者都叙述了同样的经历
And yet, most abductees report the same experiences--
白光  记忆闪回之类的
The white light, the memory flashes.
那是因为他们都看了同一类书
That's because they all read the same books,
所以他们当然会描述出同样的事情
so of course they describe the same event--
黑暗的环境  荒凉的山路
The dark, lonely road,
凭空出现的刺眼白光
the bright light out of nowhere,
记忆芯片被来回戳啊刺啊的
memories of being poked and prodded.
我相信你想说的词是"植入芯片"
I believe the word you're looking for is probed.
当然  还有外星人的植入物
And then of course there's the alien implant
用来追踪被绑架者的
that's used to track the abductees.
让我想起了
That reminds me of the lego
六岁时卡在我鼻子里的积木
I got stuck up my nose when I was 6.
你咋了来着
You what?
伙计们
Uh, guys.
鉴证组检查过那个低压舱了
C.S.U. finished going over the altitude chamber.
-一无所获  -什么
- Nothing turned up.  - What?
那台机器明明就是
I mean, that was the exact machine
我们要找的东西啊
that we were looking for,
就在玛丽和她男友
right in the building where
工作的地方
Marie and her ex-boyfriend work.
那肯定就是凶器啊
That had to have been the murder weapon.
没有血迹  没有纤维组织  非常干净
There's no blood, no tissue-- it's clean.
无论如何也说不通啊
That makes no sense whatsoever.
再查查其他的低压舱
Check other altitude chambers.
那玩意又不是随处可见的
It's not like they grow on trees.
附近肯定不只那一个
Well, that can't be the only one around.
再找找其他
And look for any other devices
能造成这种伤害的仪器
that cause the same injuries.
我尽力吧
I'll do my best.
如果不是低压舱
If it's not an altitude chamber,
那会是什么呢
then what could it be?
反正不是那个
Other than that.
蕾妮  有什么发现
Lanie, what'd you find?
没找到我想找的答案
Not the answers I was looking for.
反而发现了更多的疑问
Instead, just more questions.
多么迷人的神秘气息啊
How deliciously cryptic.
由于玛丽身上伤口的性状非常特殊
Because of the unique nature of Marie's injuries,
所以我想在进行解剖前
I wanted to thoroughly document her condition
先仔细检查下她的内部状况
before conducting the autopsy.
当我用X光扫描时
While I was taking the x-rays,
我发现这个东西嵌在她的鼻腔里
I saw this embedded in her sinus cavity.
-那是什么  -不知道
- What is that?  - I have no idea.
说我疯了吧
Call me crazy...
这东西跟外星人植入物  一模一样
That looks just like... An alien implant.
翻译：小池 苏小黛 大卫熊 千花 小易 小蛮腰
时间轴：Jimmy贝壳 之间   后期：瓜瓜   校对：大卫熊 安小七   总监：安小七
把东西植入到那种地方
What could you possibly be looking for
关于外星人的传说中
通常外星人会用探针探测人类的肛门...
你们到底是想找啥啊
by probing up there?
能商量下晚饭的事吗
Can we talk about dinner?
明白了
Oh, no.
你没能说服奶奶别进厨房瞎搅和
You couldn't convince gram to stay out of the kitchen.
我会多准备点抗酸剂和呕吐袋的
I will stock up on antacids and garbage bags.
不  不是这事  是阿什利的父母
No, it isn't that. It's Ashley's parents.
他们怎么了
What about 'em?
他爸爸是个经济学教授
He's an economics professor.
他们夫妻都是很严肃的人  老爸
The two of them are serious people, dad.
你  你可能得矜持点
Y-you may need to be more buttoned up.
我可以矜持啊
I can be buttoned up.
我要是我不够矜持了
And if I become unbuttoned,
你可以狠狠踹我一脚
You can discreetly let me know
私下提醒我一下
with a brutal kick to the shin.
我不会在场的
I won't be there.
他们觉得  只有你和奶奶去会更合适
They thought it would be better if it was just you and gram.
-你要撇下我一个人  -你能行的
- You're gonna leave me alone?  - You'll do great.
我只是想确保
I just wanted to make sure
你会给他们留下好印象
that you'll make a good impression.
相信我  我也想啊
Trust me... So do I.
经济低迷时期  人们的超前消费行为
Where do you come down on deficit spending
-你觉得该由谁负责  -谢谢
- during an economic downturn?  - Thank you.
我接受大多数经济学家都支持的说法
I take the theory that's held by most economists--
超前消费是可以接受的
That deficit spending is acceptable
只要消费的对象是公共投资
as long as it focuses on public investments,
比如基础设施  国防建设  教育研究等
like infrastructure, defense, education, research.
哇塞  这么专业  哪学来的啊
Wow. Where did that answer come from?
纽约大学一学期的经济学理论课
Semester of economic theory at N.Y.U.
这问题又是从何而来
Where did that question come from?
我只是想打开话题
I'm trying out conversation starters.
好吧  话题打开了
Well, we started a conversation,
看来你成功了  算是吧
So I guess it worked... Kind of.
其实是跟阿什利的父母吃饭的事
It's for a dinner with Ashley's parents.
他是个古板的经济学家
He's this stuffy economist, you know?
我只是想赢得他们的好感
And I just want to win 'em over,
让他们站在我这边
get them on my side.
可万一他们不喜欢我咋办
But what if they don't take to me?
-拜托  卡塞尔  他们会喜欢你的  -真的吗
- Oh, come on, Castle. They'll take to you.  - Really?
-必须的  -谢了
- Yeah.  - Thanks.
-只要你装成另一个人就行了  -算你狠
- So long as you don't act like yourself.  - Oh, nice one.
话说  这个神秘的植入物  有啥进展
So where do we stand on this mysterious implant?
那不是植入物
It is not an implant.
蕾妮说那是个金属碎片
Lanie says that it's a metal fragment,
她现在正在检测
and she's running tests on it right now.
怎么跑她鼻子里去的
How'd it get up her nose?
可能是低压舱的碎片
Well, maybe it was a piece of the altitude chamber
弹了进去
that got lodged up there.
你是说我们没找到的那个低压舱
The altitude chamber we haven't found?
"还没"  我们暂时"还没"找到的那个低压舱
Yet. The altitude chamber that we haven't found yet.
我确定只要我们找到低压舱
And I'm sure that as soon as we do,
就会助我们找到凶手
it will lead us straight to our killer.
我注意到你说的是"凶手"而不是泰德·卡特
I notice you said "Killer" and not Ted Carter.
卡特的不在场证明证实了
Yeah, Carter alibied out.
他在玛丽被杀当晚订了外卖披萨
He ordered pizza the night of Marie's murder
在8点25分签了单
and signed for it at 8:25.
30分钟足够提供不在场证明了
Alibis in 30 minutes or less.
也就是说  目前为止  我们没有人类嫌疑人
So at this point, we have no human suspects.
从定义上来说  没有嫌疑人就是没有人类嫌疑人
By definition, no suspect means "No human suspect."
貌似找到了一个嫌疑人
Well, one might be coming your way.
我检查了玛丽的单位电话记录
I checked Marie's phone logs at work.
发现在她周三离开科学中心之前
Turns out she made a 30-minute phone call
她打了一通30分钟的电话
before she left the science center on Wednesday.
给谁
To whom?
本尼·斯瑞克
Benny Stryker.
那个大名鼎鼎的本尼·斯瑞克
The Benny Stryker?
著名的本尼·斯瑞克
This Benny Stryker,
《第四类劫持》的作者
renowned author of "Taken By The Fourth Kind"?
就是他
One and the same.
一位天体物理学家和一位不明飞行物研究家
An astrophysicist and a ufologist,
他俩应该水火不容啊
isn't that like oil and water?
实际上  他们以前是同事
Actually, they used to be colleagues.
三年前
Three years ago,
他和玛丽是同一个研究团队的成员
he and Marie were members of the same research team,
但是玛丽担心他那些关于不明飞行物的言论
but Marie was worried that all his ufo talk
会毁掉团队的可信度
would destroy their credibility,
所以她把他从队伍里开除了
so she had him kicked off the team.
我听到的说法是  之后两人关系一直很紧张
From what I hear, there's been bad blood ever since.
我们在哪能找到斯瑞克
Where can we find Stryker?
被囚禁在一间冰冷的无菌室
Imprisoned in a cold white room...
怪异的脸庞盯着我们
Strange faces staring down at us...
这些影像会萦绕在我们脑海中
These are images that will haunt us.
但是它们也会使我们团结在一起  铭记这一切
But they'll also unite us and help us remember,
这不是我们的选择
We didn't choose this.
是他们选择了我们
we were chosen.
再说一遍
One more time.
这不是我们的选择  是他们选择了我们
We didn't choose this. We were chosen.
他就像是被外星人绑架过的托尼·罗宾斯
He's like the Tony Robbins of alien abductions.
看来我们有新成员了
I see we have some new members.
你们还是自我介绍一下  讲讲你们的经历吧
Maybe you'd like to introduce yourself, tell us your story.
哎呦喂
Huh.
你们真的认为
Do you actually think
玛丽的死和我有关吗
I had something to do with Marie's death?
斯瑞克先生  周四晚上9点你在哪
Mr. Stryker, where were you on Thursday at 9:00 pm?
在皇后区办新书签名会
At a book signing in Queens.
不过最近你和玛丽有过联络
But you did have recent contact with Marie.
事实上  她在周三给你打了电话
In fact, she called you on Wednesday.
谈了些什么事
What was that about?
我的确可以告诉你
You know, I could tell you,
但是我知道你不会相信的
but I see, you wouldn't believe it.
不管你说什么  我们都会客观的听取你的说辞
Whatever you say will receive a fair hearing.
我之前遇到过的情况可并非如此
Well, that hasn't been my experience.
上周在危难时刻玛丽给我打来电话
Marie called me last week in crisis.
她通过她的射电望远镜
She had picked up anomalous submicrowave bursts
发现了反常的亚微波爆炸
on her radio telescope.
那不仅仅是宇宙中的背景噪音
It was not just the background noises of the universe.
那是从附近传来
It was a signal coming from somewhere nearby
带有重复图样的信号
with a repetitive pattern.
是说联络信号吗
As in... contact?
至少她是这么认为的
Or so she believed.
她用射电望远镜阵列花更多的时间
So she booked more time on her radio telescope array
研究那部分天空的特殊情况
and studied that section of the sky,
这也就带来了麻烦
Which is when the trouble started.
什么麻烦
What trouble?
精神恍惚
Lost time.
周日有四个小时  她什么都不记得了
Four hours on Sunday, just gone.
之后她开始经历精神上的闪回
Then she started having mental flashbacks--
一间白色的屋子  一张模糊的脸质问她
A white room, a blurry face questioning her.
你是说  玛丽被外星人绑架了吗
Are we saying, Marie was abducted by aliens?
典型的迹象都出现了
The classic indicators were there.
我只是帮她把事情想明白
I just tried to help her make sense of it.
周三给你打过电话之后  玛丽离开了中心
After Marie called you on Wednesday, she left the center.
你知道她去哪了吗
Do you know where she went?
她说她要去找证据...
She said she was gonna get proof of...
她知道证据就在那
What she knew was there.
外星人的证据吗  她找到了吗
Proof of aliens? And did she?
之后没有再听到她的消息
I never heard from her again.
我以为他们
I assumed they stopped her
在她接近真相前阻止了她
before she got too close to the truth.
-谁  -政府
- Who? - The government.
我警告过她  她有可能被人跟踪了
I warned her, she was probably being followed
那些人不遗余力的...
by men determined...
试图将外星人存在这个事实保密
to keep the existence of aliens a secret.
听起来像是威尔·史密斯的电影
It's like that Will Smith movie,
不过没那么好笑
only I'm guessing a lot less funny.
这些特工真的存在  卡塞尔先生
These agents are real, Mr. Castle.
他们害怕如果我们在宇宙中并不孤独的消息
They fear the revelation that we are not alone
传出来会造成恐慌
would be too shocking.
群众会变得歇斯底里  国家会崩塌
Hysteria would break out. Nations would crumble.
正因为如此
That's why
他们才会试图让我这种信徒身败名裂
they try to discredit believers like me
减少有可能暴露事实真相的人
and eliminate people who threaten to expose the truth--
像玛丽这样的人
People like Marie.
书店确认那晚7点到9点
The bookstore confirms that Stryker was signing his opus
斯瑞克的确在签名售书
between 7:00 and 10:00 pm.
看来我们又回到了
Looks like we're back to an
没有嫌疑人的境地
empty space in the suspect column.
是啊  但是至少我们的时间线更合理了
Yeah, but at least our timeline is making more sense.
周日这个时间段  发生了所谓的"人生大事"
This whole Sunday-ish area, the life-changing event,
那就是她被绑架的时候
That's when she was abducted.
周三  她离开单位
Wednesday, she leaves work,
那是她去寻找外星人存在的证据
that's when she was looking for proof of alien life.
周四  她回来上班  情绪有所好转
Thursday, she comes back to work, feeling better,
直到她再次离开  最后...
Until she leaves and winds up...
爆发性压损致死
Explosively decompressed.
总的来说  很忙的一周
Overall, a big week.
你知道这时间线说明了什么吗
You know what this timeline shows me?
可能因服用毒品  或是身体疾病造成的
A lot of erratic behavior that could be due to drug use
一连串反常行为
or any number of medical conditions.
好吧
All right.
假设说玛丽
Let's say Marie
是一个有毒瘾的精神病患者  还得了脑瘤
is a drug-addled psychotic with a brain tumor.
她还是去寻找证据了啊
She still went looking for proof.
她去寻找她认为是证据的东西
She went looking for what she thought was proof.
不管怎样  万一她找到了呢
Whatever it was, what if she found it?
证据会在哪呢
Where would it be?
得了  卡塞尔  你不会真的相信
Come on, Castle. You don't actually believe
克林贡人是幕后主使吧
that klingons are behind this, do you?
即使以我的想象力  外星杀手也太扯了
Killer aliens is a reach, even for me.
但是政府特工为了掩盖真相痛下杀手
But government agents covering up the truth?
就不那么疯狂了
Not so crazy.
当然疯狂
Yes, it is.
我是说  到了最后
I mean, when this is all said and done,
最重要的还是要查出她被杀的地点和方式
it will all come down to where and how she was killed.
我打赌这一切
And I bet it will have nothing to do
都和秘密特工和巨大的政府阴谋无关
with secret agents or massive government conspiracies.
我跟你赌
I'll take that bet.
探长
Detective.
东西哪去了
Where did everything go?
早上两个男人带着联邦授权
Two men came this morning with a-a federal warrant.
他们把玛丽的东西装到了一辆卡车上
They loaded all of Marie's stuff into a truck.
他们是谁  哪个部门的
Who were they? From which agency?
他们只是说他们是有关部门
They just said the government.
赌债你要用小面额的给我
I'd like my payment in small bills, please.
我在司法部门的联系人
My contact at justice
声称没有开据相关玛丽办公室的授权
says no warrant was issued for Marie's office.
就是说自称是联邦探员的人
Well, then people claiming to be federal agents
拿走了她的东西
seized her property.
这到底是因为什么啊
I mean, there's gotta be an explanation.
"黑衣人"[出自电影《黑衣人》]
Men in black.
-除了这个解释  -我已经四处打听了
- Other than that. - I'll put out more feelers.
同时  你们随时向我汇报
Meantime, keep me posted.
好的  感谢长官
Okay, thank you.
玛丽找到了证据  却被他们掩盖了
Marie found proof, and they covered it up.
正如本尼·斯瑞克所说
It's just like Benny Stryker said.
你真的想让我相信这个理论吗
Do you honestly expect me to believe a theory--
这个理论可是以"如本尼·斯瑞克所说"结尾的
Any theory--that ends with "Like benny stryker said"?
还能是谁  谁会拿走她的东西
What else could it be? Who made off with all her stuff?
也许玛丽参与了政府
Maybe Marie was working on
的一项秘密项目
a classified government project,
他们没收她的一切资料
and they confiscated her data.
她的资料在办公室家具里面吗
Was her data in her furniture?
别忘了家具也被拿走了
Because they took that, too.
不知道"他们"是谁
Well, without knowing who "they" are,
我们找不到他们的
we can't find them.
知道吗
You know...
关键在于杀人凶器
the key lies in the murder weapon.
埃斯波西托
Esposito, tell me that you've
找到那个低压舱了吗
located that altitude chamber.
找到了
I did...
在哈德逊大学的物理中心
At the physics center at Hudson University.
那是五个区内唯一的一个
It was the only other one in the five boroughs.
看见没
See?
那不是凶器
It's clean.
鉴证组刚检查过了
C.S.U. just checked.
那么肯定有另一台机器
Well, there's gotta be another device
能做到同样的事
that does the same thing.
蕾妮和我查过了
Lanie and I looked into that.
我们唯一找到的就是工业真空包装机
The only thing we found was an industrial vacuum packer.
是用来处理食物的
It's used for food processing.
将市里的每一台都检查一遍
Check into every single one in town.
我们必须找出犯罪现场
We need to locate that crime scene.
卡塞尔
Castle.
证明是外星人干的  兄弟  拜托了
Just prove that E.T. did this, bro, please.
我是捉人的  不是找机器的
I hunt people, not machines.
-我会努力的  -谢谢
- I'm working on it. - Thank you.
或许我们应该将注意力
Maybe we should focus
集中在玛丽星期三的神秘行动
on Marie's mystery Wednesday trip.
卡塞尔  证明外星人的存在
Castle, finding proof of aliens
不会帮我们逮捕凶手的
will not help us catch our killer.
会有帮助的  特别是当她去了
It will if she went somewhere
有工业真空包装机的地方
with an industrial vacuum packer.
如果是的话  那不在泽西收费公路旁边
If she did, it was off the jersey turnpike.
她的易通账户显示她从九号出口下公路了
Her e-zpass account shows her getting off at exit 9.
-她去哪里了  -这很难说
- Where'd she go from there? - Hard to say.
我查过了她的信用卡  在该区域没有记录
I checked her credit cards. No activity in the area.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
我在找地图
I am mapping it.
新泽西收费公路九号出口
New Jersey turnpike, exit 9.
让我跟你们分享
Let me share with you
九号出口  都有什么可去的地方
the many wonders that await us at exit 9.
噢  有一个艺术中心
Oh, there's an arts center,
有良好景观的登山小路  能划独木舟的州立公园
some state park with scenic hiking trails and canoeing,
那里的水疗馆数量令人惊奇
an astounding amount of day spas,
还有普兰斯堡天文台
and the Plainsboro Observatory.
没错  玛丽星期三有来过
Yeah, Marie was here on Wednesday.
但她有自己望远镜的使用权限
But she had access to her own telescope.
她为什么要用这个
Why would she need this one?
玛丽平时是用射电望远镜
Marie usually worked with a radio telescope.
这是光学望远镜
This is an optical telescope.
那么她是来看
So she came here to get a visual
外太空的影像的
on something up there in space?
她说她接收到异常的信号
She said she picked up signal anomalies.
她想看看信号是从哪里来的
She wanted to see where they were coming from.
她做了图像采集  然后就走了
She took an image capture, then she left.
我们可以拿到图像的复制本吗
Could we get a copy of that image?
我查过了望远镜的硬盘驱动器
I checked the telescope's hard drive.
她消除了所有东西
She erased everything.
坐标  图像采集  全都没有了
Coordinates, the image capture, it's all gone.
她消除了所有东西
She erased everything.
她到底看见了什么
What the hell did she see up there?
玛丽·苏巴拉奥  一个清醒的科学家
Marie Subbarao, a sober-minded scientist
相信自己在截取了奇怪的
believes she was abducted by aliens
无线电信号之后被外星人绑架了
after intercepting strange radio signals.
她利用望远镜
Using a telescope,
拍下了讯息的来源
she photographs the source of the signal.
第二天  神秘地死亡了
The next day, dies mysteriously.
然后她的办公室被可疑政府特工侵入
Then her office is raided by shadowy government agents.
我没叫你去染红发
I'm not asking you to dye your hair red
然后管我叫穆德
and call me Mulder.
我只是让你考虑一下有可能
I would simply ask that you consider the possibility
玛丽知道了或者
that Marie had knowledge of
联络了上面的某些东西
or made contact with something up there.
这才害死了她
That somehow led to her death.
我们会继续展开调查
We will continue our investigation
然后破解这案子
and solve this case,
破案跟小绿人完全没有任何关系
and it will have nothing to do with little green men.
他们是灰色的
They're gray, actually.
卡塞尔  事实  真正的事实有待查证
Castle, the truth-- the real truth, is out there.
蓄电池坏了吗
Dead battery?
维修的时候刚换过了
Maintenance just replaced it.
我的电话不灵了
My phone isn't working.
我的也是
Mine isn't either.
我的手表也不走了
Neither is my watch.
你对这有合理解释的  对吧
You have a logical explanation for this, too, right?
玛丽·苏巴拉奥有一些资料
Marie Subbarao had information.
我们需要的资料
Information we need.
贝克特在哪
Where's beckett?
你是谁
Who are you?
卡塞尔在哪里
Where's castle?
我是纽约警局的探长
I am an NYPD detective.
在哪里
Where is it?
什么在哪里
Where's what?
我们都知道玛丽·苏巴拉奥
We all know what Marie Subbarao
卷入了什么事件  探长
was involved with, detective.
那些讯息不能泄露出去
That information must not get out.
没错  东西不在我们这
Yeah, but we don't have it.
在哪里
Where is it?
现在是纳粹登场
Is this the part where you bring out
手里拿着牙医钻孔机吗
the old nazi with the dentist drill?
要是你不合作的话
If you don't cooperate,
我们会有办法让你开口的
we'll find a way to get at the truth.
我们会不惜一切保护我们的生活
We'll do whatever it takes to protect our way of life.
敌人是谁
From what?
以为自己被外星人绑架了的女人吗
A woman who thought that she was abducted by aliens?
这在你的管辖范围外  探长
You're out of your league, detective.
你不晓得这事有多严重
You have no idea how deep this is.
现在东西在哪里
Now where is it?
你是谁
Who are you?
报上名来
Identify yourself.
中央情报局  国家安全局
What, CIA, NSA,
真的是黑衣人吗
M.I.B?
装扮成人类  能变形的外星人吗
Shape-shifting aliens that only look human?
谁杀了玛丽·苏巴拉奥
Who killed Marie Subbarao?
如果你继续提些你不该问的问题
If you keep asking questions you shouldn't,
你的下场会像玛丽一样
you may end up like Marie.
谁杀了她
Who killed her?
你永远也捉不到的人
No one you could ever reach.
刺杀约翰·F·肯尼迪一案呢
What about J.F.K.?
青山上的第二个枪手吗
Was it the second shooter on the grassy knoll?
黑手党雇佣的第三个枪手吗
Third shooter backed by mafia?
卡斯特罗  黑手党和卡斯特罗联手
Castro? Mafia and Castro?
好吧  不管你们在找什么
Okay, whatever you guys are looking for,
我们都不知道在哪里
we don't know where it is.
不  兄弟
Come on. No, dude.
不要  不要  啊
Come on. Don't. Don't. Ah!
不
No.
你还好吧
Are you okay?
卡塞尔  那真的发生了吗
Castle, did that really happen?
我有没有
Do I have a...
噢  不
Oh, no.
因为你有...
Cause you got a...
这太过分了
This is outrageous.
非法拘留纽约警局的探长
An illegal detention of an NYPD detective?
谁说政府不负责任的
Who says the government is unresponsive?
他们全力掩盖外星人的事
They're all over this alien cover-up.
这些人是谁
Who are these men?
类似特工什么的
Agents of some sort.
很有可能就是他们清空了玛丽办公室的人
They probably are the ones who cleared out Marie's office.
我很高兴你们没事  但没人可以
Well, I'm glad you two are all right, but no one snatches up
拐走拘留我的手下  我会调查清楚的
my people and detains 'em. I'll get into this.
那些人知道谁杀了玛丽
Those men knew who killed Marie,
而且拒绝告诉我们
and they refused to tell us.
他们也拒绝承认J·埃德加·胡佛
They also refused to confirm that J. Edgar Hoover
喜欢穿裙子[传言胡佛是同性恋]
liked to wear dresses.
被政府特工绑架了吗  说吧
Hmm. Abducted by government agents, huh? Come on.
你们俩到底做什么了
What were you two really doing?
这不是吻痕  埃斯波西托
It's not a hickey, Esposito.
你们俩都有一个
You both have one.
我倒希望是吻痕  这是注射器的痕迹
I wish it was a hickey. It's from the injectors.
现在的年轻人都是这样形容的吗
Is that what the kids are calling it these days?
他们是黑衣人
They were men in black.
真空包装机调查得怎么样了
Where are you with the vacuum packers?
目前为止我在五区内共找到了
So far, I have found over a hundred machines
上百台机器
in the five boroughs.
鉴证组正尽快检查了
C.S.U.'s checking 'em as fast as they can.
那香烟呢
And the cigarettes?
没有吻合的DNA  但那是中国牌子
No DNA match, but they are a chinese brand
只有在亚洲或唐人街的黑市能找到
only found in asia or on the black market in chinatown.
那么她有可能被外星人杀了
So maybe she was killed by an alien,
非法居留的外来人
just an illegal alien.
-那是吻痕吗  -是的
- Those hickeys? - Yes.
-不是  -我倒希望是
- No. - I wish.
好吧  技术人员全面检查了你的车
Okay. So tech just went through your vehicle.
结果发现你们是被EMP击中了
Turns out you were hit with an E.M.P.
一种电磁脉冲
An electromagnetic pulse
能破坏所有电子设备
which knocked out all the electronics.
还有这是为什么他们能找到你
And here's how they found you in the first place.
追踪器  窃听器
Tracers, listening devices.
他们肯定在监视科技馆
They must have been watching the science center.
就是在那时侯将这些放进了我的车子
That's when they put these accessories in my car.
或许那就是玛丽鼻子里面的东西
Maybe that's what was up Marie's nose.
或许他们也在跟踪她
Perhaps they were tracking her,too.
不  那不是追踪器或者植入物
No, it wasn't a tracer or an implant.
蕾妮鉴定出了这是曲霉菌
Lanie identified it as aspergillus.
这是鼻窦感染的引起的少量钙化
It's a rare calcification resulting from a sinus infection.
钙化过于密集  令它看起来像是金属
The calcification is so dense, it reads like metal.
看见没  合理的解释
There you go. Logical explanation.
是啊  也我会把追踪器伪装成成罕见...
Yeah. I would disguise my tracking implants as a rare medical...
重要的是  这帮家伙
You know, the bottom line is that these guys
急切想找回玛丽拿到的东西
were desperate to get whatever Marie took,
所以我们得抢先一步
so we gotta find it first,
因为这是找到凶手的关键
because that'll lead us to the killer.
没错  但我们不知道究竟要找什么
Yeah, but we really don't know what we're looking for.
可我们知道不在他们手上
But we do know that they don't have it.
也就是说不在玛丽的办公室里
Which means it wasn't in Marie's office.
她也许给藏起来了
She maybe hid it somewhere.
也许藏在她信任
Maybe with someone she trusted,
比较不容易被人发现的人那里
somebody under the radar.
泰德·卡特说玛丽上周三晚上
Ted Carter said that Marie gave him
把他的东西还回去了
some of his stuff back last Wednesday night.
也许还得不仅仅是他的东西
Maybe that's not all she gave him.
我不明白
I don't understand.
大部分都是书和T恤衫
It's just books and t-shirts mostly.
卡特先生 你有留意到
Mr. Carter, did you notice anything different
她给你的东西有异样吗
in the things that she gave you,
原先没有的东西
anything that wasn't there before?
没有  都是我的东西
No, it's all my stuff.
只是T恤衫  杰弗逊星船合唱团的CD
It's just t-shirts, Jefferson Starship cd--
这张CD帮我度过了
Oh! This cd got me through two weeks
两个星期的《斯道姆观望》创作瓶颈期
of "Storm Watch" Writer's block.
我不记得是2张CD的
I don't remember it being a 2-disc set.
这张没有标识
This one's unmarked.
也许是玛丽的证据
Marie's proof perhaps?
不  等等
Oh, oh, oh, no, wait.
就这样吗
That's it?
毫无盛大壮观之势
I mean, no pomp, no circumstance?
这里面的内容有可能
What's on this could shake
撼动人类存在的基石
the very foundations of our existence.
我们需要停留  品味
We need to pause and savor--
别闹了  直接放进去看看吧
Please. Let's just stick it in and get this over with.
我是说  事实是
I mean, the fact of the matter is,
这张CD也许对我们的调查
there's probably nothing of any value on that cd...
毫无帮...
to our investigati--
你说什么来着
You were saying?
不可能
No way.
仔细看这个图片  女士和先生们
Behold this image, gentlemen and lady.
我们见证了一场惊天大事
We are witness to a stunning event--
人类历史的转折点
A turning point in human history--
此刻我们知道  我们并不孤单
The moment we knew... We were not alone.
因为谁能否认这个是...
For who can deny that this...
外星人宇宙飞船呢
is an alien spacecraft.
看起来是挺像的
It does kinda look like one.
是的  但这个图像
Yeah, but this image?
这肯定修过的  对吧  贝克特
I mean, it's gotta be doctored. Right, Beckett?
我不知道
I don't know.
你在说什么
What are you saying?
你是说  你觉得这是真的
Are you saying, you think that this is real?
这个
Well...
这看起来不像修过的
It doesn't look doctored.
搞清各位的态度  以便确认各位都说了什么
Okay, just for clarity, so we know later who said what,
你承认有可能
You are conceding that it is a possibility
这是一艘外星人宇宙飞船
that this is an alien spaceship?
我说的是
What I am saying
我们现在知道了那些特工要找的东西
is that we now know what these agents were after.
就差一点
That close.
在我看来
And as far as I'm concerned,
让更高层人员去处理吧
let a higher pay grade deal with it.
我们现在有筹码和神秘特工谈判
We now have leverage that we can use with our mystery agents.
怎么做  我们又不能直接打给他们
How? It's not like we can just call 'em up? Mm.
我们有一盒窃听器
W--uh, we do have a box of bugs.
除了蝙蝠侠的电话就这个最赞了
It's the next best thing to a batphone.
我们有你要的东西  你知道我们的位置
We have what you want. You know where we are.
你真觉得这能成功吗
You really think that's gonna work?
请坐
Please take a seat.
东西在哪里
So where is it?
休想
Not a chance.
我想以此做个交换
I want something in return--
杀害玛丽·苏巴拉奥的凶手的名字
The name of Marie Subbarao's killer.
女士优先
Ladies first.
你为何给我看这个
Why are you showing me this?
这是玛丽在天文台拍下的
It's the photo that Marie took from the observatory
外星人飞船
of the alien ship.
我得告辞了
I'll be on my way now.
等等  我们说好的
Wait a minute. We had a deal.
你说你有我要的东西  但是你没有
You said you had what I want. As it happens, you don't.
你不能走  玛丽·苏巴拉奥
You're not leaving. Marie Subbarao was murdered
被极其凶残的手法杀害
in the most awful way imaginable,
而凶手依然逍遥法外
and her killer is still out there.
你欠她的  告诉我们凶手的名字
You owe it to her. Give us that name.
也许她并不是你们认为的那样
Maybe she isn't who you think she is.
你这是什么意思
What's that supposed to mean?
如果不是这样  那又是什么
I mean, if it's not this, then what?
为什么要纠缠一位天体物理学家
Why all of this fuss over an astrophysicist
她只是分析无线电信号
who analyzes radio signals?
除非她分析的是秘密
Unless what she analyzed was secret.
就是这么回事  对吧
That's it, isn't it?
她拦截了机密信息
She intercepted classified information.
你说过她拿走一些
Yeah, you did say that she took something
涉及国家安全的重要东西
that was vital to our security.
我们在案发现场发现中国香烟
And we found Chinese cigarettes at the crime scene.
她给中国人工作吗
Was she working with the Chinese?
你要么现在告诉我们真相
Look, either you tell us the truth now,
要么我们把情况交给媒体
Or we take what we know to the media.
你觉得他们会发表吗
What makes you think they'll print it?
他们也许不会
Oh, they probably won't.
但我知道很多博主愿意发表
But I know more than a dozen bloggers who will.
更别提我那50多万
Not to mention over half a million
微博上的书迷
of my own followers on Twitter.
我说的绝对不能泄露出去
Nothing I say can leave this room.
我们向你保证
You have our word on that.
上个月  我们确定一个敌国间谍
Last month, we determined that an enemy operative
拦截了太平洋舰队与国防部之间的
Had intercepted classified, coded data streams
绝密数据流
between the pacific fleet and the pentagon.
你认为是玛丽干的
You think it was Marie.
拦截传送的时间与
The intercepted transmissions coincided
玛丽将她的无线电天文望远镜
with Marie's tasking her radio telescope
对准我们的卫星的时间一致
to point at our satellite,
这根本不是
which was nowhere near where she was
她原本应该研究的对象
supposed to be doing her research.
那这不是飞碟的照片
So that wasn't a photo of a UFO.
而是你们的间谍卫星
That was your spy satellite.
但真正的破坏是她下载的数据
But the real damage done is the data she downloaded,
我担心现在在中国人手上
which I fear is now in the hands of the Chinese.
那是谁杀了她
So then who killed her?
我认为是她的中间人
Her handler, I imagine.
这个中国人肯定知道我们在调查他们
The Chinese must have known we were on to them.
他们很聪明
They were smart enough
把这事弄成像是她男友干的
to make it look like the boyfriend did it.
谁是中间人
Who's this handler?
中国情报人员
Someone from Chinese intelligence.
我们无法核实他的身份
We were never able to identify him.
不管他是谁  你们永远抓不到他
Whoever he is, you'll never catch him.
结束了
It's over.
这从来没有结束
It's never over.
在书中  我以一种新颖大胆的看法
In the book, I take a bold new look
审视市场线性集合
at the linear aggregation of markets.
早就该这样了
It's about time someone did.
阿什利告诉我你也是作家
So Ashley tells me you're an author as well.
卡塞尔先生  说说你的书吧
Tell me about your writing, Mr. Castle.
我不看畅销小说
I don't read popular fiction.
我发现大部分都愚蠢且华而不实
I find most of it crass and tawdry.
是的  没错
Yes. Right.
嗯  我
Well, I, uh...
我觉得我的写作
I think of my writing
像是通过人类行为来进行性格研究
as character studies in human behavior,
寻求人类行为的真正动因
looking into the heart of what makes people tick.
比如  是什么让一个普通人
For instance, what would make an ordinary person,
比如你
like yourself,
犯下滔天大罪
commit an act that's unusually heinous
或是一些
or some...
不符合人物性格的...
out of character...
抱歉  我失陪一下
Would you excuse me for a-a moment?
玛丽的行为不正常
Marie was acting out of character.
合格的间谍
What self-respecting espionage agent
怎么会行为怪异
would act strangely
导致有可能泄露自己的身份呢
and risk blowing her cover?
也许她不是真正的间谍
Maybe she wasn't the real spy.
那也许解释了蕾妮刚送来的化验结果
Well, that might explain the test results that lanie just sent over.
玛丽身体里检测出麻醉药
Marie had traces of sodium pentothal in her system.
有人给她用了说真话麻醉药
Somebody gave her truth serum?
也许那才是真正的间谍   白房间  提问题
Maybe it was the real spy. The white room, the questions--
那就是斯瑞克认为她被外星人绑架的原因
That's why Stryker thought she was abducted by aliens.
如果玛丽不是间谍
Well, if Marie wasn't the spy...
那么真正的间谍就是能够
Then the real spy is someone with access
进入科学中心使用无线电天文望远镜的人
to that radio telescope at the science center.
我现在就过去
I'm heading over there right now.
我尽快赶到
I'll meet you there as soon as I can.
再来点酒吗
More wine?
又找到一张申请  把望远镜观测方向
Got another request here, redirecting the telescope
对准了卫星的坐标
to the satellite coordinates.
就跟其它申请一样  都是玛丽签的
Signed by Marie, just like all the others.
不管这跟她一贯的行为有多不符
Well, out of character or not,
看来她就是我们要找的间谍
it looks like she was the spy after all.
等一下
Wait a minute.
这两个签名不一样
These two signatures are different.
a的写法不同
The...the a's don't match.
没错
You're right.
看看还有谁那样写a
And look who else makes an "a" like that?
查尔斯·沃恩博士
"Dr. Charles Vaughn".
他仿冒玛丽的签名  使她看上去
He forged her signatures to make it look as though
像是那个拦截卫星传送信号的人
Marie was the one intercepting the satellite transmissions.
那么也许玛丽发现了假冒她签名的申请
So maybe Marie saw a request with her fake signature,
于是她起了疑心
and she got curious.
所以她自己递交了申请
So she put in a request of her own
用望远镜来查看那个区域
to have the telescope scan that part of the sky.
她就是在那个时候截获了那些奇怪的信号
So that's when she intercepted the weird signals.
在那之后  她有一段时间精神恍惚
After that, she lost time.
她跟本尼·斯瑞克说了这件事
And then when she told Benny Stryker about it,
而他以为她是被外星人绑架了
he assumed that she had been abducted...
她的确是被绑架了  只不过不是被外星人
Which she had been, only not by aliens,
而是被沃恩博士绑架了
by Dr. Vaughn,
他给她下了药  想问出她究竟知道多少
who drugged her to figure out how much she knew.
当他意识到她已经接近真相了
When he realized how close she was,
-他就把她除掉了  -没错  但是
- he got rid of her.  - Yeah, but he's the one
是他把低压舱的线索告诉我们的
who told us about the altitude chamber.
因为他知道
Yeah, because he knew
那会把我们引向玛丽的前男友
it would lead us to Marie's ex-boyfriend.
沃恩博士不见了  他不在家
Dr. Vaughn is gone. He's not at his place.
你知道我在他家找到了什么吗
But you know what is?
三瓶麻醉剂
Three vials of sodium pentothal.
知道他去哪了吗
Any idea where he went?
不知道  但他是匆忙离开的
No, but it looks like he left in a rush.
打给运输安全署  禁止他搭乘任何航班
Call TSA and have him put on a no-fly list,
有消息就通知我  他开溜了
and keep me posted. He's on the run.
如果他听说我们要了那些申请表来查验的话
If he heard we asked for those request forms,
他可能就觉得事情不妙了
he would've been tipped off.
他可能早就有逃亡计划了
He probably had an escape plan in place,
就以防他的身份暴露
just in case his cover was blown.
他还有那些
And Chinese handlers
可以把他偷渡出国的中国中间人
who can smuggle him out of the country.
我不是消极
Not to be negative,
但是逮到这家伙的几率不大呀
but the odds of catching this guy are not great.
除非我们能得到某位政府探员的帮助
Unless we enlist the help of a certain government agent
他跟我们一样迫切地想要抓到他
who wants him just as bad as we do.
你们还真是阴魂不散呀
I may want to put you guys on my friends and family plan.
我们现在认为沃恩博士就是那个间谍
We now believe that Dr. Vaughn is the spy.
玛丽发现了  于是他就把她给杀了
Marie figured it out, and then he killed her.
我不得不同意你的观点
I'm inclined to agree,
但这就意味着我们局之前是白忙了一场
which leaves the agency with some egg on its face.
你之前说你是哪个局的来着
And which agency did you say that was again?
我没说过  我们深入调查过沃恩博士
I didn't. We dug deeper on Dr. Vaughn.
发现他有赌博的爱好
Turns out he has a fondness for gambling.
他在大西洋城的一间中国人开的赌场里
He ran up quite the tab at an Atlantic city casino
花了一大笔钱  在那之后
controlled by the Chinese. After that,
他就对那些中国人言听计从了
they owned him.
你知道沃恩博士现在在哪吗
Do you know where Dr. Vaughn is now?
我知道该从哪查起
I know where to start looking.
我可以通过他的手机号码对他做三角定位
Using his cell phone number, I can triangulate his position.
他肯定担心会被追踪
Well, he's gotta be worried about being tracked.
大概已经关机了吧
He probably turned it off.
-那我们再给他开机就是了  -你有这本事
- Then we'll just turn it back on.  - You can do that?
我们那天晚上不就把你们的手机关了吗
We turned off your phones, didn't we?
没错  还有我们的车
Yeah, and the car.
他在唐人街的仓库区
He's in the warehouse district in Chinatown.
运河街1400街区
1400 block of Canal Street.
能再拉近点吗
Could we get a closer look?
-看到他了  -厉害
- There he is.  - Fancy.
这离玛丽的弃尸地点
That's just a few blocks away
只有几个街区而已
from where we found Marie's body.
也许那就是案发地点
Maybe that's where he killed her.
那家伙是谁  等一下
And who is that guy? Oh, wait.
他就是那个抽烟的人
He's the cigarette-smoking man.
又叫做安邱
Otherwise known as Ung Kyu.
他是高级别的中国情报探员
He's a high-level Chinese intelligence agent.
这么说我们的疑犯正在见他的中间人
So our murder suspect is meeting his handler.
也就是说数据可能还在沃恩博士手上
Which means Dr. Vaughn may still have the data.
那我们就去抓他吧
Well, then let's go get him.
那些无人侦察机
Where are the predator drones,
黑色直升机
the black helicopters,
还有扯着绳索从天而降的飞虎队去哪了
all those SWAT teams rappelling down on ropes?
经费削减  为了我们国家的安全
Budget cuts. It's vital to our national security
我们必须活捉这些人
that we take these men alive.
这些人是训练有素的探员  他们舌头底下
These guys are trained agents. They probably have
也许藏着氰化物胶囊呢  一旦被捕就自尽
cyanide capsules in their teeth in case they're caught.
到时候再担心这个吧
We'll worry about their teeth when the time comes.
巡逻车封锁了附近五个街区内
Patrol cars have closed off all streets
-所有的街道  -空中支援也马上就到
- in a 5-block radius.  - And air support's on the way.
好的  追捕计划是什么
All right. What's the plan?
沃恩的手机信号不见了
Vaughn's cell phone signal has gone dark,
也就是说他到地下去了  根据我们的资料
which means he's underground. According to our intel,
这栋楼有个巨大的地下室
this building has an extensive basement
总共有两个入口
with two methods of ingress.
实际上  这部分街区的多数地下室
Actually, most of the basements on this side of town
都连着很多逃生通道  是非法移民在
are linked through doorways used as escape routes
移民局排查时逃跑用的
for illegals in case of an INS raid.
所以你是说沃恩和邱有可能在
So you're saying that Vaughn and Kyu could be
隔壁的任何一栋楼里咯
in either of the adjoining buildings as well?
这就是纽约
Welcome to New York.
我们走
Let's go.
纽约警局  待着别动
NYPD. Stay where you are.
一点钟方向有个真空包装机
That's a vacuum packer at 1:00.
看来我们找到凶器了
Looks like we found our murder weapon.
你们见过这个人吗
Have you seen this man?
走吧  走吧
Go, go.
你出国读过书吗
Semester abroad?
没  跟我以前喜欢看的一个电视剧学的
Nah, a TV show I used to love.
干得好
Ah. Nice job.
谢谢
Thanks.
跪下
Get on your knees.
不  等一下  求你了
No. Wait! Please!
我干掉了玛丽  你让我干的事我都干了
I-I got rid of Marie. I did everything you asked.
等等  等等  等等  我还可以帮你的
Wait. Wait, wait, wait, wait. I can still help you.
等等  等等  等等
Wait. Wait, wait.
求你了  我还可以帮到你的  求你了
Please. No, I can still help you. Please.
纽约警局  把枪放下
NYPD! Drop that gun.
蹲下  快点
On the ground. Now.
氰化物胶囊
Cyanide capsule!
恶心  是口香糖  虚惊一场
Ew! Gum. False alarm.
数据在哪
Where is the data?
在他口袋里的一个闪存里
In a...USB drive in his pocket.
这次行动能给我们换个奖章吗
Think we'll get a medal for this?
这件事从没发生过
This never happened.
看来我也不能把这件事写到微博上了
Guess that means I can't put this on twitter.
沃恩已经什么都招了
Vaughn's already spilling his guts.
那是  差点被干掉  哪还有忠诚可言啊
Yeah, a near execution will shake your loyalties like that.
凭他的供词和间谍行为的指控
Between his confession and the espionage charges,
他跟安邱的下半辈子就要在
he and Ung Kyu will spend the rest of their lives
联邦监狱里过了  这都多亏了你
in federal prison, thanks to you.
-还有卡塞尔  -没错  还有卡塞尔先生
- And to Castle.  - Yes, and Mr. Castle.
我可以跟贝克特探长单独谈谈吗
Might I have a private word with detective Beckett?
当然
Of course.
宝贝  听着  关于家长见面那件事
Hey, sweetie. Look, um, about the parental review.
我知道我搞砸了  对不起
I failed, and I know, and I'm -- I'm sorry.
他们  他们觉得我很棒吗
They...they found me fascinating?
跟我们  他们想跟我们一起去露营吗
Camping with u -- they want to go camping with us?
不  不  不会  这很好
No. No, no, it's -- no, that -- yeah, that'd be great.
肯定会很好玩的
That'd be so much fun.
我也爱你  拜拜
I love you, too. Bye.
他跟你说什么了
So what'd he tell you?
他告诉我一些机密情报
Uh, he told me something in confidence.
是什么
What?
我也想告诉你  卡塞尔
Well, I wish I could tell you, Castle,
可是这是机密
but it was classified.
他告诉你什么机密了
Well, what did he tell you that was classified?
外星人吗  还是不明飞行物的真相
Was it about aliens? The truth about UFOs?
你到底要不要告诉我
Are you gonna tell me
还是你就想让我一直猜下去
or you just gonna make me keep guessing?
我不知道  看你猜也挺有意思的
I don't know. This guessing thing is kinda fun.
-好吧  是罗斯威尔那件事吗  -不是
- All right. Was it about what happened at Roswell?  - No.
-五十一区那件事吗  -不是
- Area 51?  - No.
尼斯湖怪兽是真的
- Loch Ness monster is real?  - Yeah.
-真的吗  -才不是
- Really?!  - No.
-骗到我了  他们在控制气候  -不是
- Ah. You had me. They're controlling the weather?  - No.
-控制我们的思想  -不是
- Our thoughts?  - No.
控制我们的消费习惯  说起消费
Our buying habits? Actually, speaking of shopping,
我看过一篇很有趣的
I read this really interesting...